<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../xsl/wmui-style-guide.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE dict>
<dict page="introduction" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<item key="introduction-heading">
Introduction
</item>
<item key="introduction-1">
Wikimedia is a global movement built by a diverse audience.
</item>
<item key="introduction-2">
This guide provides a general design direction that can be useful for different kinds of interactive projects. Designers and developers will find design recommendations to solve general problems, so that they can focus on the specific needs of their projects.
</item>
<item key="introduction-3">
This is an ongoing work, you can always check online <xhtml:a href="https://wikimedia.github.io/WikimediaUI-Style-Guide/">the latest released version of the guide</xhtml:a>. You can help making it grow.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-heading">
How to contribute
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-1">
You can participate in many ways. The documentation is available in a Git repository with the design assets needed for your project. You can get all of them, change anything and send the changes back.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-getting-heading">
Getting the design repository
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-getting-1">
The <xhtml:a href="https://github.com/wikimedia/WikimediaUI-Style-Guide/">WikimediaUI Style Guide repository is available to download</xhtml:a>. It contains this documentation, templates and further design resources. Select the “clone or download” button to get the repository.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-committing-heading">
Committing changes
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-committing-1">
If you have <xhtml:a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git">Git</xhtml:a> installed on your system, <xhtml:a href="https://help.github.com/articles/cloning-a-repository/">cloning</xhtml:a> is preferred way to get the contents since it allows you to contribute back. Technically changes can be submitted as usual in Git.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-committing-2">
In order to publish the updated contents to be available live, go to the repo and launch the following command from a terminal: <xhtml:code>git push -f origin master:gh-pages</xhtml:code>
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-beyond-heading">
Changes beyond content
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-beyond-1">
With the above instructions you can easily modify the content of the guidelines by adding new recommendations, making corrections or adding examples in the form of images or videos. Furthermore, you can also help improving how this documentation looks and works.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-beyond-2">
When modifying aspects such as the CSS styling you'll need to rebuild the documentation files using <xhtml:a href="http://gruntjs.com/">Grunt</xhtml:a> (which requires <xhtml:a href="https://docs.npmjs.com/getting-started/installing-node">Node.js and npm</xhtml:a>). The first time you have to run <xhtml:code>npm install</xhtml:code> in a terminal from the guideline main folder in order to get all the needed dependencies. Every time you want to rebuild the CSS files for the documentation you just need to launch the <xhtml:code>grunt</xhtml:code> command in a terminal, also from the main folder.<br />
We're using <xhtml:a href="http://stylelint.io/">stylelint</xhtml:a> to ensure the CSS <xhtml:a href="https://github.com/wikimedia/stylelint-config-wikimedia/">aligns with our</xhtml:a> <xhtml:a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:Coding_conventions/CSS">coding conventions</xhtml:a>.
</item>
<item key="introduction-contribute-beyond-3">
These are requirements to provide our contributors a reliable environment and our viewers a performant experience.
</item>
</dict>
